He always wanted to be special... but he never expected this!
Teen Wolf is a comedy, fantasy, romance film directed by Rod Daniel.
When a shy teenager's new-found powers help him score at basketball - and with
the popular girls - he has some pretty hairy decisions to make.
Scott Howard, played by Michael J. Fox.
Harold Howard, played by James Hampton.
Lisa 'Boof' Marconi, played by Susan Ursitti.
Rupert 'Stiles' Stilinski, played by Jerry Levine.
Lewis, played by Matt Adler.
Pamela Wells, played by Lorie Griffin.
Teen Wolf is a 1985 American coming-of-age comedy film directed by Rod
Daniel and written by Jeph Loeb and Matthew Weisman.
Fox stars as the title character, a high school student whose ordinary
life is changed when he discovers that he is a werewolf.
James Hampton, Scott Paulin, Susan Ursitti, Jerry Levine, Matt
Adler, and Jay Tarses appear in supporting roles.
Filming took place from November to December 1984.
Teen Wolf was released on August 23, 1985, by Atlantic Releasing
Corporation, and received mixed reviews from film critics.
It was a commercial success, grossing over $33 million domestically on a $4
million budget, with the worldwide gross being over $80 million.
The film's success spawned a titular franchise, including an animated series adaptation in 1986, a sequel film in 1987, the
supernatural live action drama series that aired on MTV from 2011 to 2017, and its continuation film in 2023.
The film explores themes of high school, trainer,
training, coming of age, werewolf.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.